# Patrick Dugan

www.dailydoog.com dugan.pat@gmail.com 716.481.5567

# Experience

# **Technical Strategist, Google Inc.**

March 2011 to August 2013:: Mountain View, CA

I most recently worked as a member of an analytics team at Google with a focus on building predictive models that proactively identified fraud occurring across Google's payment platforms. Specifically, I classified and prevented fraud attempts against first and third party integrations of Google Wallet. I also designed and built internal fraud reporting tools.

# Technical Development Program, Liberty Mutual Insurance Group

May 2010 to March 2011:: Boston, MA

I participated in the Liberty Mutual Technical Development program and was a member of the company's first mobile development team. I designed mobile application interactions and user interfaces for Android, iOS, and the mobile-web. Additionally, I helped conduct several consumer usability studies centered around Liberty's mobile portfolio.

# Systems Support Analyst (Intern), Polaris Global Mobility Software

March 2010 to May 2011 :: Bellevue, WA

I tested and filed bugs against custom integrations of an expatriate employee payroll management solution. Additionally, I provided technical assistance and support for Fortune 500 clients that included Thomson Reuters, Johnson & Johnson, and Goldman Sachs. I also lead a project to develop an internal collaborative knowledge-sharing repository.

### Web Developer (Intern), BuffaloGreenArt.com

May 2008 to September 2008:: Buffalo, NY

I designed, constructed, and deployed an eCommerce solution for a sustainably focused clothing company. I worked closely with non-technical company founders to create an accessible and easy-to-navigate digital storefront. I also helped integrate multiple 3rd-party payment and reporting solutions.

# Education

Graduate

# **University of Washington**

August 2013 to September 2014 (projected) :: Seattle, WA

Master of Science; Human Computer Interaction & Design; GPA: 4.0 (in progress)

#### Undergraduate

#### **University of Washington**

September 2008 to June 2010 :: Seattle, WA

Bachelor of Arts; Information Systems; GPA: 3.54 cumulative

#### Individual Study

#### College of San Mateo

September 2011 to July 2013 :: San Mateo, CA

Computer Science (Individual Study); GPA: 4.0 cumulative

#### San Francisco Academy of Art University

June 2012 to July 2013 :: San Francisco, CA

Web Design & New Media (Individual Study); GPA: 3.8 cumulative

# Frontend & Markup

CSS XML JSON Django HTML5 Microdata Microformats

#### **Tools**

Balsamiq Illustrator Axure RP Fireworks Dreamweaver

#### Languages

Java VB.net Python Javascript

#### **IDEs**

Coda Eclipse Visual Studio

#### Frameworks

Android Microsoft.NET Google App Engine

### Databases

SQLite MySQL Google Cloud SQL Microsoft SQL Server App Engine Datastore

#### UX

Usability Testing Information Architecture Hi/Low-Fidelity Prototyping

#### **About Me**

I enjoy creating elegant, useful and usable user-experiences

I am especially passionate about the mobile-web

I love hiking, camping, running and generally anything that involves being outdoors

> I also blog whenever I can about a variety of topics

Patrick Dugan Resume :: 1 of 3

www.dailvdoog.com :: dugan.pat@gmail.com :: 716.481.5567

# **Notable Technical Projects**

### **Liberty Mutual Mobile Channel Development**

October 2011 to March 2012:: Liberty Mutual Insurance:: Boston, MA

- · Developed technical business requirements for Liberty Mutual's first iOS, Android, & mobile-web applications
- · Assisted in execution of multiple mobile usability studies and subsequent incorporation of usability improvements
- · Created low & high-fidelity wireframes, user storyboards, and XML android activity layouts

# **USMC Pro-Fitness Android Application**

February 2012 :: Freelance :: Berkeley, CA

- · Designed, developed, and published an android fitness tracking application
- Drove 7,000+ unique application installs with backwards compatibility through Android 2.2 (Froyo)
- · Currently working to switch from 3rd party support libraries to native ActionBarCompat in SL revision 18

### Google Event Connect Redesign

October 2012 to August 2013 :: Google, Mountain View, CA

- Drafted and prototyped improved visual redesign for major components of an internal event coordination application
- · Built functional HTML/CSS/Javascript prototypes for use by Event Connect team and relevant stakeholders
- · Consolidated information architecture while also improving event creation, discovery, and management workflows

# **Activities**

# UW Laboratory for Usability, Testing, and Evaluation (LUTE) Research Assistant

September 2013 to Present :: University of Washington :: Seattle, WA

### **Undergraduate Research Learning Community Mentor**

September 2013 to Present :: University of Washington :: Seattle, WA

### **Google Transparency Imagery Report Lead Designer**

April 2013 to August 2013 :: Google :: Mountain View, CA

#### **Google Research Event-Connect Lead Designer**

October 2012 to August 2013 :: Google :: Mountain View, CA

#### **Liberty Mutual Technical Development Program Inductee**

June 2010 :: Liberty Mutual :: Boston, MA

#### University of Washington Foster Information Systems Mentorship Program

2009 to 2010 Academic Year :: University of Washington :: Seattle, WA

#### **University of Washington Resident Adviser**

2009 to 2010 Academic Year :: University of Washington HFS :: Seattle, WA

#### **United States Marine Corps Officer Candidate**

June 2009 to September 2009 :: USMC Officer Candidate School :: Quantico, VA

#### **Boy Scouts of America; Eagle Scout**

March 2005 :: Boy Scouts of America :: Buffalo, NY

# **Awards**

#### Google Product Quality Operations Gold Award (2x)

June 2012; March 2013 :: Google :: Mountain View, CA

www.dailydoog.com :: dugan.pat@gmail.com :: 716.481.5567

# Awards (continued)

# Forrester Research Mobile App Design Best-Practices Citation

April 2011 :: Liberty Mutual :: Boston, MA

### University of Washington Residential Life Event Director of the Year

2008 to 2009 Academic Year :: University of Washington :: Seattle, WA

# **Rochester Institute of Technology Computing Medal Scholarship**

June 2006:: Rochester Institute of Technology:: Rochester, NY

# **Posters**

Inspiring Future Engineers & Improving Husky Quarterback Performance with Google Glass

August 2013 :: University of Washington; Electrical Engineering:: Seattle, WA

Patrick Dugan Resume :: 3 of 3

www.dailydoog.com :: dugan.pat@gmail.com :: 716.481.5567